Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create a health bar for our boss.
If we just scroll down and go over to our Widget Blueprint folder.
Right click on the enemy health bar, duplicate it and call this our boss Health bar.
If we open this up and set the progress bar, go to style and make the background image our boss health
bar empty and make the film image our boss Health bar.
Now.
Oppo's health looks kind of weird.
It doesn't look like the image here.
If we scroll down and go to feel color and opacity, we can see it has this blue tint.
If we just change this to white, our boss helper will no longer have a tint anymore.
So just go, okay?
And then anchor this bar to the top of our screen and expand it across the top of our screen.
So I'm going to make my end up like this.
So position your post health bar somewhere like this.
Then go over to the graph and we can delete these nodes.
And if we actually go back to our boss blueprint, create a new variable and call this max elf.
And change this to be a float.
Then if we go to event, we can play, event we can play.
We are going to drag in our max health and set its value to be whatever our bosses health is.
So drag us in and connect these nodes here.
If we compile this and go back to our boss Health Widget blueprint.
And if we just delete this variable and create a new variable and call this boss.
And undesirable type.
Change this to be a boss blueprint, object, reference and just make sure this is instance editable
and expose on spawn.
You'll see why we do that in a second.
And if we just drag in our bus, drag up here and get the health.
And connect this into the first body.
And then drink.
Okay.
And get the metals.
And connect us into the second value here.
Then if we compile this and go back to our boss blueprint after we set our bosses max health, we're
going to drag up here and look for create widget.
The widget we're going to create is going to be the Boss health bar.
And for the boss because we made it's wearable expose on Swan.
When we're creating our boss health widget, we can determine the value of this wearable.
So drink up here and look for self.
Then right click on this value.
Promote it to a variable and call it our boss reference.
And then we're going to add this to our viewport.
So our drag and add to viewport.
And connect us into here.
Now, whenever our box is damaged, we're going to drag in our boss hard reference and call the Update
health bar.
And this will update our boss's health bar accordingly.
And we can just connect this into here.
And then finally, when we kill our boss, we're going to remove our health bar from our screen.
So I'll just drag in the boss reference and drag off there and look for remove from parent.
And this will remove the boss health bar when it dies.
And I'm just going to change my boss's health back to ten.
And now if I go compile and play, when I start my level, we can see my post as helper.
Whenever I attack my boss, it's helpless.
Should decrease.
So I'll take it.
Its health will decrease.
So when I kill my boss, it disappears.
And then the boss disappears.
With this, we have created our bosses health bar.